you
hello and welcome to Sherpa seminars my name is Don Keonion I'm the marketing
manager for Sherpa Digital Media and today I'm going to be covering our top
10 tips for a memorable virtual event here at Sherpa we've helped some of
the Fortune 500 and global 1000 companies host truly memorable and highly
attended virtual events in the last few years so we want to make sure that we
can impart some of that experience and guidance on to you for your next
virtual event these first two tips are focused on how to get people to your
event make sure that the user experience for any person coming to your event
page is as seamless and modern as possible more and more people are browsing
content on mobile devices or tablets so you want to make sure the design is
mobile friendly and responsive you also want to make sure it's inviting and
engaging and that there aren't any technical barriers to entry between your
viewers and the content this means making sure that the site loads quickly
making sure the player is embedded in a way that matches the look and feel of
your brand making sure the players branding reflects your brand in a whole
host of other design elements and technical elements you want to keep in
mind when building out your event experience now once you've optimized your
event page and really honed in on that look and feel it's important to get as
many people to register for your event as possible there will always
inevitably be some drop off between the amount of people who register and the
amount of people who actually show up so it's important to promote your event
via email social media paid ads whatever channels you deem appropriate to get
as many people registered as possible for the event at minimum you should
promote the event at least two weeks prior but ideally you have at least four
weeks of time to promote your event in advance this gives you plenty of time to
follow up with people send up multiple promotions in order to get people
registered before the day of the event these next few tips are focused on the
content itself you want to make sure that the production quality is as high as
possible given whatever resources you have available whether you have
professional cameras and lighting or not there's always a way that you can up
the production quality and really ramp up the immersiveness if you have
professional cameras and lighting equipment that's great a good rule of
thumb to keep in mind when setting up for the show is to have at least one camera
isolated for each speaker and then an additional camera for a wide angle or
alternate angle shot this