Welcome to Shostomonars. My name is Don Keonion. I'm the marketing manager for
digital media and today I'm going to be covering our top 10 tips for a
memorable virtual event. Here at Shia we've held some of the Fortune 500 and
Global 1000 companies host truly memorable and highly attended virtual events
in the last few years. So we want to make sure that we can impart some of that
experience and guidance onto you for your next virtual event. These first two
tips are focused on how to get people to your event. Make sure that the user
experience for any person coming to your event page is as seamless and
modern as possible. More and more people are browsing content on mobile devices
or tablets. So you want to make sure the design is mobile friendly and responsive.
You also want to make sure it's inviting and engaging and that there aren't any
technical barriers to entry between your viewers and the content. This means
making sure that the site loads quickly, making sure the player is embedded in a
way that matches the look and feel of your brand, making sure the player's
branding reflects your brand. In a whole host of other design elements and
technical elements you want to keep in mind when building out your event
experience. Now once you've optimized your event page and really honed in on
that look and feel, it's important to get as many people to register for your
event as possible. There will always inevitably be some drop off between the
amount of people who register and the amount of people who actually show up. So
it's important to promote your event via email, social media, paid ads, whatever
channels you deem appropriate, to get as many people registered as possible
for the event. At minimum you should promote the event at least two weeks
prior. But ideally you'd have at least four weeks of time to promote your
event in advance. This gives you plenty of time to follow up with people, send
up multiple promotions in order to get people registered before the day of the
event. These next few tips are focused on the content itself. You want to make
sure that the production quality is as high as possible given whatever resources
you have available. Whether you have professional cameras and lighting or not.
There's always a way that you can up the production quality and really ramp up
the immersiveness. If you have professional cameras and lighting equipment
that's great. A good rule of thumb to keep in mind when setting up for the show
is to have at least one camera isolated for each speaker and then an
additional camera for a wide angle or alternate angle shot. This